Guide to the Giuliano Garavini Collection AD.MC.038
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
- Minutes of OPEC meetings, 1976-1980; 66.1 Megabytes in 23 PDF documents.
  - 52nd meeting: Minutes of the 52nd Meeting of the Conference, held in Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates, December 16 - 17, 1978 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_061)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics included review of the 1979 budget, the reports of working parties on petrochemicals and statistics, the report of the meeting of chiefs of OPEC National Oil Companies, and the question of how OPEC should respond to inflation and the continued devaluation of the US dollar. To the latter, OPEC announced that it would raise prices of crude in a moderated fashion in accordance with inflation, but not at the full rate of inflation. Rene Ortiz of Ecuador was also appointed as the new Secretary General, and proposals to add languages other than English (especially Arabic) as official languages of OPEC was once again discussed.
    PDF, 68 pages, 4 MB.
  - 53rd meeting: Minutes of the 53rd Extraordinary Meeting of the Conference, held in Geneva, Switzerland, March 26 - 27, 1979 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_062)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics focused largely on pricing of oil and perceived discrepancies between prices charged by OPEC member state producers and outside oil companies, and the impact this was having on consumers, especially those in developing countries. A resulting acceleration in the increase of OPEC prices per barrel on crude was announced.
  - 53rd meeting: Report: The Effects of Price Adjustments on Balance of Payments and Inflation in Consuming Countries, March 1979 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_063)
    PDF, 20 pages, 524 KB.
  - 54th meeting: Minutes of the 54th Meeting of the Conference, held in Geneva, Switzerland, June 26 - 28, 1979 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_064)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics discussed included impact of inflation on oil revenues and the purchasing power of developing countries, the replenishment of the OPEC Special Fund to aid such countries, critiques of industrialized countries for their perceived unwillingness to assist developing countries, an increase in the price per barrel of crude from OPEC countries to address this situation, and the proposal to price OPEC crude using a basket of currencies rather than relying solely on the US dollar. The negative public image of OPEC was also addressed, and the need for the organization to respond, particularly in developing countries.
    PDF, 103 pages, 7 MB.
  - 54th meeting: Summary of the Proceedings of the Third Meeting of the Chief Executives of the OPEC National Oil Companies, Vienna, April 9 - 10, 1979 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_065)
    Representatives in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. The primary topic was to address findings of a working group on staffing, education and training for the oil industry in OPEC member states.
    PDF, 7 pages, 363 KB.
  - 54th meeting: Working paper: Iraqi Proposal for the Creation of a Long-Term International Fund to Assist Developing Countries Against Inflation., June 1979 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_066)
    PDF, 10 pages, 644 KB.
  - 55th meeting: Minutes of the 55th Meeting of the Conference, held in Caracas, Venezuela, December 17 - 20, 1979 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_067)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics included the expansion of the OPEC Special Fund, both in size and scope, to assist other developing countries and increase solidarity between them and OPEC, the development of OPEC public relations, responses to the continuing challenges of inflation and devaluation of the US dollar, and reports of the Working Party on Petrochemicals and the fourth meeting of the Chief Executives of OPEC National Oil Companies. Includes text of opening address by Venezuelan President Luis Herrera Campins.
    PDF, 117 pages, 8 MB.
  - 55th meeting: Report: Crude by Crude Netback Up-dating of Batelle Netback Model (Specifnet). Energy Studies Department., December 13, 1979 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_068)
    PDF, 30 pages, 2 MB.
  - 55th meeting: Report: Current Market Situation. Energy Studies Department, OPEC Secretariat, December 1979 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_069)
    PDF, 52 pages, 2 MB.
  - 55th meeting: Report: OPEC Crude Oil Price Differentials. Energy Studies Department, December 1979 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_070)
    PDF, 40 pages, 2 MB.
  - 55th meeting: Report: Refined Product Prices and Taxes in Western Europe. Energy Studies Department, OPEC Secretariat, December 1979 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_071)
    PDF, 80 pages, 3 MB.
  - 56th meeting: Minutes of the Fifty-Sixth (Extraordinary) Meeting of the Conference, held in Taif, Saudi Arabia, May 7 - 8, 1980 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_072)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics included the Long-Term Strategy Report, which was accepted with some reservations by a few member states, the upcoming meeting of Foreign Ministers of OPEC member states as a venue for addressing relations with industralized countries, the upcoming meeting of OPEC heads-of-state in Baghdad, the pricing of natural gas in relation to crude oil, and the decision of member countries not to replace Iran's withheld exports on the international market.
    PDF, 55 pages, 4 MB.
  - 57th meeting: Minutes of the Fifty-Seventh (57th) Meeting of the Conference, held in Algiers, Algeria, June 9 - 11, 1980 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_073)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics included the financial and auditor reports for 1979, the supplementary budget for 1980s, reports on the fifth meeting of chief executives of National Oil Companies and the fourth meeting of the working group on petrochemicals, the proposed establishment of an OPEC News Agency, planning for the summit of leaders of OPEC member states, further development of the long-term strategy of OPEC, the raising of the per-barrel price of crude oil as a strategy to combat stockpiling of oil reserves, and aligning pricing strategies of natural gas with those used for crude oil in member states that produce both. Also includes texts of speeches by conference president Humberto Calderon Berti of Venezuela, and President Chadli Benjedid of Algeria.
    PDF, 91 pages, 6 MB.
  - 57th meeting: Report of the Fourth Meeting of the Working Party on Petrochemicals, Vienna, April 8 - 10, 1980 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_074)
    Representatives in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Indonesia, Iran, Kuwait, Nigeria, Saudi Arabia. The report looked at projected production and pricing of petrochemical products over the next decade, operational problems of member countries in developing their industries, and defining means of cooperation among member states in a market environment, among other issues.
    PDF, 41 pages 1 MB.
  - 57th meeting: Summary of the Proceedings of the Fifth Meeting of the Chief Executives of the OPEC National Oil Companies, Vienna, April 21 - 22, 1980 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_075)
    Topics covered
    Representatives in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Venezuela. Topics included the survey of training institutions available to staff in member states, the report of the working group on refining operations that met in Jakarta the previous February, and ways to coordinate purchases of goods and services.
    PDF, 11 pages, 585 KB.
  - 58th meeting: Minutes of the Fifty-Eighth (58th) (Extraordinary) Meeting of the Conference, held in Vienna, September 17, 1980 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_076)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. The main topic was member states should best respond to the surplus of oil on worldwide markets, attributed to stockpiling of reserves by consumer nations, and the impact this was having on oil revenues in member states. The resulting decision was to lower the price per barrel of crude and freeze prices for the time being.
    PDF, 26 pages, 1 MB.
  - 59th meeting: Minutes of the Fifty-Ninth (59th) Meeting of the Conference, held in Bali, Indonesia, December 15 - 16, 1980 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_077)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics included approval of the 1981 budget, the proposed educational institute for training personnel working in the petroleum industry, the extension of the incumbent Secretary General's term by one year, and the report of the 52nd meeting of the Economic Commission, upon whose recommendations per barrel prices of crude were raised once again. Discussion was also given to the war that had recently broken out between two member states, Iran and Iraq, and attempts to resolve their differences from within OPEC. Also included were paraphrased texts of speeches from conference president Dr. Subroto (Indonesia) as well as Indonesian President Suharto.
    PDF, 62 pages, 2 MB.
- Minutes of OPEC meetings, 1980-1985; 87 Megabytes in 20 PDF documents.
  - 60th meeting: Minutes of the Sixtieth Meeting of the Conference, held in Geneva, Switzerland, May 25 - 26, 1981 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_078)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics included the financial and auditor reports for 1980, reports of the 7th informal meeting of Chief Executives of the National Oil Companies, the Committee of Experts for the formation of the OPEC Institute for Higher Education, and the proposal for the formation of an energy trust fund for Research and Development at Oxford University. Reports of the 53rd and 54th meeting of the Economic Commission were presented, and discussion continued about the long-term strategy of OPEC. Marc Saturnin Nan Nguema of Gabon was appointed Secretary General. The conference adjourned on its first day to offer condolences at the Ecuadorian consulate, after having learned of the death of Ecuadorian president Jaime Roldos Aguilera in a plane crash earlier that day.
    PDF, 122 pages, 7 MB.
  - 61st meeting: [no records extant] (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_079)
  - 62nd meeting: Minutes of the Sixty-Second (62nd) Meeting of the Conference, held in Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates, December 9 - 11, 1981 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_080)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics addressed included the 1982 budget, the report of the Economic Commission, continued discussions on the formation of an OPEC higher education institute, and how to best counter negative publicity against OPEC, and the need for a concerted public relations campaign. Also includes the text of the opening speech by Mana Said Otaiba, the Minister of Petroleum and Mineral Resources for the United Arab Emirates.
    PDF, 132 pages, 8 MB.
  - 63rd meeting: Minutes of the Sixty-Third (63rd) Extraordinary Meeting of the Conference, held in Vienna, March 19 - 20, 1982 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_081)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. The meeting primarily addressed responses to current market conditions (such as drop in consumer demand and increase in production by non-OPEC states), which led them to confirm the price increase per barrel of crude as agreed at their previous meeting, to set a ceiling on production, and to address the issue of price differentials.
    PDF, 28 pages, 2 MB.
  - 64th meeting: Minutes of the Sixty-Fourth (64th) Meeting of the Conference, held in Quito, Ecuador, May 20 - 21, 1982 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_082)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics addressed included discussion of the report of the Ministerial Committee, which led the conference to retain ceilings on production adopted at the previous meeting, and a review of the report of the 56th meeting of the Economic Commission, Also included was the text (paraphrased) of the opening speech by Osvaldo Hurtado Larrea, president of Ecuador.
    PDF, 99 pages, 6 MB.
  - 65th meeting: Minutes of the 65th (Extraordinary) Meeting of the Conference, held in Vienna, July 9 - 10, 1982 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_083)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. The topics discussed were primarily in response to the report of the third meeting of the Ministerial Committee, which had meant to address the issues of pricing and production ceilings, but during the meeting, the continuing issue of price differentials was raised as well.
    PDF, 116 pages, 5 MB.
  - 66th meeting: Minutes of the Sixty-Sixth Meeting of the Conference, held in Vienna, December 19 - 20, 1982 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_084)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics included approval of the 1983 budget, and the report from the sixth meeting of the Ministerial Committee, which recommended maintaining the production ceiling in light of continued reduced demand for oil.
    PDF, 37 pages, 2 MB.
  - 67th meeting: Minutes of the 67th (Extraordinary) Meeting of the Conference, held in London, March 14, 1983 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_085)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. The main topics of discussion were to set the price per barrel of crude at $29, and to keep a production ceiling of 17.5 million barrels per day.
    PDF, 29 pages, 2 MB.
  - 68th meeting: Minutes of the Sixty-Eighth Meeting of the Conference, held in Helsinki, Finland, July 18 - 19, 1983 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_086)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics included the financial and auditor's reports for 1982, and the reports of the Ministerial Monitoring Committee and the Economic Commission, and a review of the long-term strategy of OPEC, since market conditions had greatly changed since the last time they had addressed that several years earlier. Also included was the text of the opening address by Finnish Prime Minister Kalevi Sorsa.
    PDF, 59 pages, 4 MB.
  - 69th meeting: Minutes of the Sixty-Ninth Meeting of the Conference, held in Geneva, December 7 - 9, 1983 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_087)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics included the 1984 budget, the reports of the Ministerial Monitoring Committee and the 59th Economic Commission meeting. These reports confirmed that the market had weakened and led them to hold off raising the ceiling on production and to maintain current prices. The decision to appoint a new Secretary General, pending from previous meetings, had again been deferred, due to objections from some members (such as Iran) as to the selection process.
  - 70th meeting: Minutes of the 70th Meeting of the Conference, Vienna, July 10 - 11, 1984 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_088)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics included the financial and auditor's reports for 1983, discussion of the reports of the Ministerial Monitoring Committee and the 60th meeting of the Economic Commission Board, and the meeting of the executives of national oil companies. No new Secretary General was chosen, and it was agreed to maintain current price levels and the production ceiling, and to reach out to non-OPEC producing countries to better coordinate pricing and production.
    PDF, 86 pages, 6 MB.
  - 70th meeting: Report: Report by His Excellency Mana Saeed Otaiba, Chairman of the Ministerial Monitoring Committee, to Be Presented to the 70th Meeting of the Conference, July 1984 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_089)
    Provided the committee's assessment of market conditions, outlook for oil demand, and results of the $5 reduction in price per barrel of crude.
    PDF, 10 pages, 356 KB.
  - 70th meeting: Report: Progress Report on the Long-Term Strategy presented to the 70th Meeting of the Conference by His Excellency Ahmed Zaki Yamani...Chairman of the Long-Term Strategy Committee, July 1984 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_090)
    The report summarized the committee's discussion to date of four key issues: developing a long-term strategy for pricing policies, OPEC relations with other oil-exporting countries, OPEC relations with developing countries, and relations with industrialized countries. It was acknowledged that industrialized countries had countered OPEC's strategies in pricing and demand successfully, and that OPEC needed to think more strategically about its own response to that.
    PDF, 11 pages, 1 MB.
  - 71st meeting: Minutes of the 71st (Extraordinary) Meeting of the Conference, Geneva, October 29 - 31, 1984 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_091)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Observers: Egypt, Mexico. The main focus of the meeting was responding to price cuts from non-OPEC producers Norway and the United Kingdom, and member state Nigeria, and the reassertion of the existing price per barrel of $29 for member states, and implementation of a cut in production to 16 million barrels per day. The issue of price differentials among different types of crude was revisited, and a committee was formed to pursue that topic further.
    PDF, 51 pages, 4 MB.
  - 72nd meeting: Minutes of the Seventy-Second (72nd) Meeting of the Conference, Geneva, December 19 - 29, 1984 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_092)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Observers: Brunei Darussalam, Egypt, Malaysia, Mexico. Topics included approval of the budget for 1985, and discussion of the reports of the Ministerial Monitoring Committee and the Ministerial Committee on Price Differentials, and in regard to the latter, proposed a table of prices for different types of crude. A new Executive Committee was also formed to ensure that price and production controls were enforced among member states.
    PDF, 152 pages, 11 MB.
  - 72nd meeting: Report: Eighteenth (18th) Meeting of the Ministerial Monitoring Committee, Geneva, 18 December 1984 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_093)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Indonesia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Topics discussed included lack of success in achieving aims of reduction of output, lack of credibility of OPEC due to differential in pricing systems.
    PDF, 2 pages, 117 KB.
  - 72nd meeting: Report: Report on OPEC's Long-Term Strategy presented by Ahmed Zaki Yamani, December 1984 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_094)
    The main topic of the report was of Yamani's (and his committee's) efforts to reach out to non-OPEC oil producing nations, both from the developed (United Kingdom, Norway) and developing (Egypt, Mexico, Malaysia) countries, as well as the Soviet Union, to gauge their possible levels of cooperation with OPEC in setting a pricing structure on oil. As a result of Yamani's meetings with representatives from each of those countries, he invited Egypt, Mexico and Malaysia to attend OPEC meetings as observers.
    PDF, 7 pages, 565 KB.
  - 73rd meeting: Minutes of the Seventy-Third (Extraordinary) Meeting of the Conference, Geneva, January 28 - 30, 1985 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_095)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Observers: Brunei Darussalam, Egypt, Malaysia, Mexico. The main topics were discussion of the reports of the Ministerial Monitoring Committee, the Executive Council, and the Ministerial Committee on Price Differentials. In regard to price differentials, a table of prices for different types of crude were adopted by most membrs, with Algeria, Iran, and Libya dissenting and Gabon abstaining.
    PDF, 84 pages, 6 MB.
  - 74th meeting: Minutes of the Seventy-Fourth Meeting of the Conference, Geneva, July 22 - 25, 1985 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_096)
    Delegations in attendance: Algeria, Ecuador, Gabon, Indonesia, Iran, Iraq, Kuwait, Libya, Nigeria, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, United Arab Emirates, Venezuela. Observer: Mexico. Topics included review and discussion of reports from the 62nd meeting of the Economic Commission Board, the Ministerial Monitoring Committee and the Minsterial Executive Council. In terms of the price differentials, prices were slightly reduced on different types of crude, which most members approved with the exceptions of Algeria, Iran, and Libya, which refused to support that.
    PDF, 109 pages, 7 MB.
  - 75th meeting: Minutes of the Seventy-Fifth (Extraordinary) Meeting of the Conference, Vienna, October 3 - 4, 1985 (Box E-records AD_MC_038, Object E-records AD_MC_038_097)